Guide to the Sarah Refo Mason Papers
Yale University Divinity School Library
- Re. life and work of Sarah Refo Mason, Series IX
  - Correspondence with colleagues and others
    - Li Zhao-xin and Huang Xing (Box 39, Folder 411)
    - Yaohui Liang (Box 39, Folder 412)
    - Kathleen Lodwick (Box 39, Folder 413)
    - Cynthia McLean (Box 39, Folder 414)
    - Larry MacDonald (Box 39, Folder 415)
    - Donald MacInnis (Box 39, Folder 416)
    - Karen Masen (Box 39, Folder 417)
    - Suzanne Miers (Box 39, Folder 418)
    - Arlene Neher (Box 39, Folder 419)
    - Barbara Nelson (Box 39, Folder 420)
    - Norman Owen (Box 39, Folder 421)
    - Carl Parrini (Box 39, Folder 422)
    - Barbara Posadas (Box 39, Folder 423)
    - Albert H. Quie (Box 39, Folder 424)
    - Shen Yuin-Yin, Li Kuo-Fang (Box 39, Folder 425)
    - James Shirley (Box 39, Folder 426)
    - Arthur Tai (Box 39, Folder 427)
    - Aadel Brun Tschida (Box 40, Folder 428)
    - Nobuya Tsuchida (Box 40, Folder 429)
    - Nancy Tucker (Box 40, Folder 430)
    - Steve Upton (Box 40, Folder 431)
    - Francis Johnstone White (Box 40, Folder 432)
    - Helen White (Box 40, Folder 433)
    - Franklin Woo (Box 40, Folder 434)
    - Grace Yaukey (Box 40, Folder 435)
    - Marilyn Young (Box 40, Folder 436)
    - Joyce Lin-Yueh Yu (Box 40, Folder 437)
  - Correspondence with archives and organizations
    - Archives (Box 42, Folder 471)
    - National Archives (Box 42, Folder 472)
    - University of Oregon--missionary collections (Box 42, Folder 473)
    - Presbyterian Historical Society (Box 42, Folder 474)
    - Yale Divinity School Library (Box 42, Folder 475)
    - Chinese Historical Society of America (Box 42, Folder 476)
    - China Mission Group (Box 42, Folder 477)
    - National Conference of Chinese American Studies, 1980 (Box 42, Folder 478)
    - Northwest Regional China Council, 1993-1994 (Box 42, Folder 479)
    - Midwest Regional Seminar on China, 1979 (Box 43, Folder 480)
  - Additional collected material and notes
    - Lewis S. C. Smythe, "The Changing Missionary Message"; W. P. Mills, "Aids to an Understanding of Sun Yat Sen"; H. F. Rowe, "Preparation of An Adequate Chinese Ministry", 1929 (Box 40, Folder 442)
    - Articles by A. J. Fisher (Box 40, Folder 443)
    - Miscellaneous notes, 1988-1992 (Box 43, Folder 481)
    - Peter Cheng, "Agricultural Development and Rural Political Changes", 1976 (Box 43, Folder 482)
    - Cheung Hin Yao (Box 43, Folder 483)
    - A Message from Chinese Christians to Mission Boards Abroad, 1949 (Box 43, Folder 484)
    - The Marriage Law of the People's Republic of China (Box 43, Folder 485)
    - Articles by John Collier on Cultural Revolution in Canton, 1968 (Box 43, Folder 486)
    - "China: A Demographic Crisis", 1963 (Box 43, Folder 487)
    - Frank Dikotter, "Hairy Barbarians, Furry Primates and Wild Men: Cultural Representations of Hair in Modern China", 1993 (Box 43, Folder 488)
    - Leigh Kagan articles (Box 43, Folder 489)
    - Penne Laingen, "Letters of an American Teacher in China, 1910-1913", 1987 (Box 43, Folder 490)
    - Angus McDonald, "Revolution and counter-revolution in Hunan Province", 1975 (Box 43, Folder 491)
    - James M. McCutcheon, "Protestant Missionaries in Asia and the Pacific: Agents of Change for What Purpose?" (Box 43, Folder 492)
    - J. Medard thesis and memoir: French Protestant minister's thesis written in early 1920s on Protestant missions in China. Medard attended the World Student Christian Federation conference in Peking (Beijing) in 1922. (Box 24, Folder 157)
    - National Geographic on China, 1927 (Box 43, Folder 493)
    - Joseph Needham (Box 43, Folder 494)
    - Ellen C. Parsons, "A History of Woman's Organized Missionary Work", 1893 (Box 43, Folder 495)
    - Murray A. Rubinstein, "Christianity in China: One Scholar's Perspective of the State of the Research in China Mission and China Christian History, 1964-1986" (Box 43, Folder 496)
    - Article on Arthur Rugh, 1926 (Box 43, Folder 497)
    - Articles by Ruth and Victor W. Sidel (Box 43, Folder 498)
    - Articles by Edgar Snow (Box 43, Folder 499)
    - Lyman P. Van Slyke, "Glimpses of Guerrilla War: North China, 1940 and 1941", 1992 (Box 43, Folder 500)
    - Wen-hsing Wu, "Mainland Chinese Migrants in Taiwan in the 1920's: Some Social Issues and Problems", 1989 (Box 43, Folder 501)
    - Diary of Margaret McCa, 1906 (Box 9, Folder 55)